[narrator] There were 950 years
of samurai history,
yet it only took a single battle
for an entire breed of warriors…
[men shouting]
…to vanish.
-[dramatic music playing]
-[shouting continues]
[man 1 shrieks]
-[grunting]
-[groaning, yelping]
Forward! Come on!
Forward!
[dramatic music intensifies]
[man 1 panting]
-[grunts]
-[man 2 yelps]
-[man 1 grunting, panting]
-[man 3 shrieks]
[men shouting, groaning]
[man 1 panting]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[tense music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[both grunting]
[squelching]
[cymbal crashing]
It's over!
Victory is ours!
[men cheering]
Raise the smoke signal!
[flare bursts]
[man 4 shouts] Yeah!
-[cannon firing]
-[cannonball whistles]
[men shouting]
What's that?
What's going on?!
Stand down! Stop it!
It's over! Stop!
-[cannonballs whistling]
-[gunshots]
[men yelping, groaning]
[coughing]
-[groaning]
-[men screaming]
[explosions]
[bullets whizzing by]
[yelps]
Stop!
Stand down!
[battle noises fade]
[breathing heavily]
[high-pitched ringing]
[unsettling music playing]
[unsettling music intensifies]
[gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[woman coughing, vomiting]
[woman breathing heavily]
[wind whistling]
Shino.
-I'll help you.
-Sorry, I didn't mean to wake you.
[gasps, whimpers]
Toya, can you get me a hand towel?
-'Kay.
-[girl coughs]
Open up.
Father…
[man] Hm?
It hurts.
Rin. You'll be fine.
You'll feel better soon.
[sighs]
I'm sorry.
I was the first one who was sick.
Everything is my fault.
It's not your fault.
Thank you.
FUCHU, KANAGAWA
[exhales, groans softly]
[straining]
[unsettling music playing]
-[men screaming]
-[gunshots, explosions]
[breathing shakily]
[man] Stand down! Stop it!
It's over! Stand down!
[whimpering]
[battle noises fade]
[panting]
[somber music playing]
[narrator] A decade after the Boshin War…
[child crying]
…the new government's
modernization policies
reclassified the samurai as "shizoku,"
stripping them
of their privileges and employment.
Meanwhile, people's lives were devastated
by the widespread cholera outbreak.
[man coughing]
-[child] Mama! Mama!
-[sighs]
[man sighs] Saga-san.
I don't know what to say.
You can't keep
bringing me worthless things.
[whispers] I'm sorry, but… Please…
Don't make this harder
than it needs to be.
Swords have been banished
for two years now.
You know as well as I do
those days are behind us.
Saga-san… Please, don't do this to me.
I'll take anything you can give.
Once cholera passes,
I'll repay your kindness.
Please,
I'm begging you.
[sighs]
Shino and your daughter…
Are they doing that badly?
[Saga breathes shakily]
[sighs]
Hey.
Go get some sugar and salt for him.
[woman] All right.
I don't need your sword.
Keep it.
[exhales] Thank you so much.
[man sighs]
What a time we're living in.
How did it ever come to this?
[man 1] When did this get put up?
[man 2] I don't know.
It wasn't there yesterday, right?
[man 1] It says it's in Kyoto.
[man 2] "An opportunity
to win 100,000 yen."
-[man 1] A hundred thousand?
-It can't be true.
What sort of nonsense is that?
I doubt this is even real.
These people must think we're all fools.
But if it were real,
you could feed
a whole family for a century!
[man 2 laughs] That seems
too good to be true, right?
[man 1 chuckles] Here. I'll have one.
PARTICIPANTS WANTED
ASSEMBLE AT TENRYUJI TEMPLE IN KYOTO
[Saga] "Those who excel in martial arts…
Tenryuji Temple…"
"Prize…
100,000 yen."
-[man 2] Whatever this is, it's unusual.
-[man 1] Could we compete?
-[man 2] I don't know.
-[whistle blowing]
Hey! What are you doing?
-[man 1] What's the problem?
-[official] Hold it right there!
-Can you tell us what this is?
-Give me the pamphlets, all of you!
-We just wanna know.
-This has nothing to do with you.
-Hand it over! Step back!
-You're just as guilty!
[Saga sighs]
[Shino shouts] Rin!
-Rin!
-[gasps]
[Shino] Rin!
Rin!
-Rin!
-[Shino] Rin! Rin!
Rin!
Rin! Rin! [breathing shakily]
-Rin! Rin? Rin?
-Rin!
[Rin] Father…
I… I couldn't…
I couldn't save Mother and Toya.
I'm really sorry.
[somber music playing]
Rin!
Rin…
[Saga] Rin…
[inhales sharply]
[sobbing]
Forgive me.
[monk chanting]
[gasping, panting]
[sobbing]
[insects chirping]
[inhales deeply]
ASSEMBLE AT TENRYUJI TEMPLE IN KYOTO
AT MIDNIGHT ON MAY 5TH
[breathing heavily]
[bell chimes]
[exhales deeply]
Shujiro-san?
Shino.
I'm really sorry,
but I'll be gone for a little while.
I've found a job
that could bring in some money.
If I get the money, we'll be safe,
and so will everyone in the village.
Are you going to draw your sword again?
No, don't worry.
It won't come to that.
[brooding music playing]
Please stay safe.
I'll come back to you.
All right.
[dramatic music playing]
KYOTO
-[indistinct chatter]
-[folk music playing]
[man] Oh, by the way,
you saw the papers, right?
I did. They say it's part
of a government sword hunt.
[boy] Mom, please, can we go?
We wanna see.
It's not safe. You're not going
anywhere near Tenryuji Temple.
-[girl] Why? But I really wanna go!
-[woman] That is final.
-[Saga exhales]
-[woman] Welcome.
[man] Welcome.
-Saga? It can't be.
-Hello, Yahei.
It's been a while.
It's been a while indeed.
Oh, wait. Saga, are you involved as well?
So you've seen others like me?
Yes. I've seen a couple.
I've noticed a few guests carrying swords.
Mm.
And do you know anything about it?
Well, rumor has it that some survivors
of the old shogunate forces
are seeking allies for revenge.
But it's nothing more than rumors.
There's no telling what's true.
Is that right?
[dog barking]
[exhales deeply]
[straining]
[unsettling music playing]
[breathing shakily]
-[knocking]
-[Yahei] Saga-sama, may I come in?
Yes.
You're getting ready to go, I see.
Be careful.
Kyoto feels different tonight.
It feels just like the old days.
That same iron scent
of blood hangs heavy in the air.
Look after yourself, Saga.
-[exhales]
-[ominous music playing]
TENRYUJI TEMPLE
[indistinct murmuring]
Are you here to participate?
Doors.
-[man 1] Whoa!
-[man 2] They opened the gate!
-[guard] Enter.
-[exhales]
[doors slam]
[indistinct chatter]
[ominous music intensifies]
[breathing shakily]
[man 3] Hey, hey, hey!
[man 4] Shut up!
[man 5] You shut up!
[exhales deeply]
[breathing shakily]
[man 6] Ugh.
Ah, look at all this. This chaos.
[chuckling]
Everyone's blinded by the fortune, right?
Wouldn't surprise me
if someone drew a sword before it starts.
Oh, uh, I'm sorry. Uh…
I need the sound
of my own voice to keep calm.
[laughs, clears throat]
Oh, by the way… Tachikawa Kouemon,
a former samurai from Kaga.
Wait, you're from Kaga?
So the papers made it that far?
[breathing heavily] Yes, in fact, uh,
I've been speaking with folks all day.
From Hokkaido all the way to Ryukyu.
There's someone from every region.
And you know what?
I'd say if the hosts are willing
to go that far,
then that means it's feasible
that the 100,000 isn't a lie after all.
[ominous music ends]
[crowd murmuring]
[indistinct muttering]
[gasping]
Huh?
[foreboding music playing]
Who's that?
The time has come at last.
Let us begin.
I will proceed with the opening.
First off, I'd like
to thank each and every one of you
for being here tonight.
I'll introduce myself.
Enju is my name.
-It's an honor to meet you.
-[indistinct murmuring]
Tonight, you will enter into a game
that will truly test your spirit
and your skill
and your physical limits.
[man 7] Get on with it. Come on.
-[man 8] We didn't come for a game.
-[man 7] We're not here all day.
Yes, yes. I don't blame you.
You just play a game
and walk away with a fortune?
A fortune
that you aren't even sure exists?
I imagine you're quite anxious.
[clicks tongue]
[foreboding music intensifies]
[crowd murmuring indistinctly]
What do you think that's for?
[gasping, clamoring]
There's enough gold in this pot
for ten years of luxury and ease.
And yet, compared to what you could earn
if you choose to stay,
this is nothing.
[gasping, cheering]
[Tachikawa laughs]
[Enju] So the question is how you earn it.
Ah…
Well…
The thing is
you cannot back out
once you've been told the rules,
no matter what.
[crowd muttering indistinctly]
I will now begin
counting down from thirty.
If you have no desire to join us tonight,
feel free to step out now.
-Thirty. Twenty-nine.
-[man 9] Oh, now he's counting.
[clamoring]
-Twenty-eight.
-[man 10] Tell us the rules!
Twenty-seven.
-[man 11] I'm not backing out!
-Twenty-six.
-Twenty-five.
-[man 10] Tell us the rules!
[man 12] That's enough!
-[crowd goes quiet]
-Huh?
[faint murmuring]
[tense music playing]
Stay where you are.
I'm Ando, Fourth Division, Kyoto PD.
Hey, that's An-Jin, the Swift Wind!
[man 13] He's right.
It's An-Jin, the Swift Wind!
[Enju] Wow.
Kyoto PD, huh?
Anyway, as long as you're here,
you're considered a participant as well.
You don't know who you're dealing with.
Of course I do. An-Jin, the Swift Wind.
So good with a sword
that even the Shinsengumi
wouldn't have stood a chance.
Or at least that's what
you like to tell everyone, right?
Because that's the truth.
You're all under arrest
for breaking the sword ban.
[clamoring]
There's no need to be a spoilsport.
We're just having some fun.
Who's the mastermind? Where is he?
No idea.
Show me your hands, or I'll cut them off.
Is that right?
I guess that means
that you won't participate?
Oh…
Pity, isn't it?
Hm. You're crazy.
-[dramatic music playing]
-[gasping]
[gasping]
Pardon me
for the brief interruption, folks.
[crowd murmuring faintly]
Anyway… Let the countdown recommence.
Twenty-four.
-[man 14] Wait. What the hell? Wait.
-Twenty-three.
Twenty-two.
-[man 14] What do I do?
-Twenty-one. Twenty.
-[man 15] He killed that guy.
-[Enju] Nineteen.
-Are you leaving?
-[Enju] Eighteen…
-[man 16] I'm out of here!
-[man 17] Hey, wait, don't give up!
[Enju] Sixteen.
-[man 18] I'm not backing out!
-[Enju] Fifteen…
[man 18] I'm doing this!
Even if I quit now,
I don't think I'd be any better off.
[Enju] Twelve.
Eleven.
Ten.
-[man 19] Not gonna end up like that guy!
-[Enju] Nine. Eight.
Seven.
-Six. Five.
-[man 19 yells]
Four.
Three, two, one.
[dramatic sting]
That's amazing.
The bravery you're showing
impresses me deeply.
[breathing shakily]
[indistinct murmuring]
MAP OF TOKAIDO ROAD
TENRYUJI TEMPLE
All right. This game you are agreeing
to take part in is called…
"Kodoku."
Naturally,
every game comes with its rules.
Take one of these.
[guard 1] Write down your name.
[Enju] I will now explain them in detail.
-[guard 2] Wear this around your neck.
-Are we not supposed to take it off?
Rule one.
From this moment on,
Tokyo will be your final stop.
Rule two.
The main gates of Tenryuji Temple,
Ise Province's Seki,
Mikawa Province's Chiryu,
Totoumi Province's Hamamatsu,
Suruga Province's Shimada,
Sagami Province's Hakone,
Musashi Province's Shinagawa.
You have to go through
all seven of these locations.
107 KOUEMON TACHIKAWA - 108 SHUJIRO SAGA
[guard 2] Put this on.
Rule three.
You are going to need
a certain amount of points
in order to pass through each province.
-[guard 2] Wear this around your neck.
-[Enju] Rule four.
Under no circumstances
are you to tell anyone else about this.
[guard 2] Sign here.
[Enju] Rule five.
You are required to be in Tokyo no later
than June 5th, one month from today.
Rule six.
You cannot abandon the game at any point.
That said, should your wooden tag
be removed from your body,
and ten counts pass,
it will count as a withdrawal.
[guard 2] Wear this at all times.
[breathing shakily]
Rule seven.
-Anyone who dares break the rules…
-[man 20 screaming]
[crowd clamoring]
Ten. Nine.
-[man 20] No! I don't wanna do it!
-Eight.
-Seven.
-[man 20] Let me out!
[Enju] Six.
Five.
Four.
-Open the gate!
-[Enju] Three.Two.
One.
[screaming]
[gasping]
[groaning]
[breathing shakily]
[dramatic music playing]
Rule seven.
Anyone who dares break the rules
is going to earn their punishment.
This is insane.
You didn't say anything
about getting killed!
-[clamoring]
-You liar!
No! You little liar!
[man 21] That's not
what we signed up for! Hey!
-[man 22] I want out of here!
-[man 23] We're gonna die here!
[indistinct shouting]
Now be quiet!
[crowd falls silent]
I gave you a choice, didn't I?
And you've made your decision.
No turning back.
When you heard about the 100,000 yen,
your mind was already set.
You are part of this game now.
[breathing heavily]
Let's get back to it.
A total of 292 participants
are gathered here tonight.
Each of you has a wooden tag
which counts as one point.
Which means you already hold one point.
In order to get through Tenryuji
and head to the next post,
you'll need at least two points.
And you'll need 30 points
to enter Tokyo, the final destination.
SHINAGAWA, MUSASHI PROVINCE - 30 POINTS
NIHONBASHI
Figured out how to earn points yet?
[gasps]
Looks like some of you already have.
No way. He… can't be serious.
[foreboding music playing]
Nothing is off limits.
Tear the tags from each other's necks!
[dramatic music playing]
[Enju] I see many here
who endured the chaos of a bygone age.
True survivors among the samurai.
And they are the ones most worthy
of receiving such a generous prize.
Now, show us the courage
that defines the samurai legacy.
Excuse me. Should we team up?
Some people came
all the way here with their friends.
It's better than going solo, right?
If you want, I could help you
with my sword fighting skills.
All right. I'm going to start a ten-count,
and the game will begin.
[breathing shakily]
Why is there a child here?
Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
-Seven.
-[swords swishing]
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Then I will be waiting, in Tokyo.
Or rather…
in Edo, the city lost since that day.
Hopefully, our paths cross once more.
[dramatic music intensifies]
And begin!
[crowd breathing heavily]
[indistinct muttering]
[grunts]
-[groans, gurgles]
-[crowd gasping]
[tense music playing]
That's one point.
-[groans]
-[crowd clamoring]
[riveting drums playing]
[grunting, screaming]
[gun firing]
[breathing shakily]
[groans]
[music distorting]
[man 24 grunts]
[suspenseful music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[laughs]
[grunting]
[grunts]
[screams]
She's mine! [cackles]
[straining]
[grunts, laughs]
[breathing shakily]
[suspenseful music intensifies]
Let's do this! [grunts]
[yells]
[woman grunts]
[groans]
[grunting]
[distant clamoring]
[gun firing]
[footsteps approaching]
[Enju] Sakura.
Does this bring back any… memories?
No.
[chuckles softly]
[guard] Congratulations
on making it through.
Your wooden tags, please.
[gunshots]
Kikuomi Ukyo.
First one to make it through.
You're truly a Guardian of the Nobility.
-What foul plan are you weaving right now?
-I'm planning to be in Tokyo, waiting.
Confirmation complete.
Well…
Safe travels.
[eerie music playing]
-[dramatic music playing]
-[panting]
[man 1] Father!
[gunshots]
Oh. Uh, thank you so much.
Do you want to survive?
I do, yes.
I wanna live to save my mother, sir.
Don't leave my side
until we get out of here.
I'll keep you safe.
All right.
[man 2] I found him,
the one with the girl!
-They're under the building!
-Let's go.
[breathing heavily]
I got one!
[grunting]
[screaming]
[yells]
Go!
[man 3 grunts, yelps]
-[crowd gasping, clamoring]
-[screams]
-[man 4] Got it! [grunts] Oh yeah!
-[girl shrieks] Give it back!
-[straining] Give it back!
-[shooter] Ten.
-[grunts]
-[shooter] Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Give it back!
[shooter] Five.
Four.
Three.
-[man 4 screams]
-Two.
-One.
-[grunting]
[panting]
[grunts] Hang on!
[man 5] Who took my tag? Hand it over!
[clamoring]
-Hang on!
-[girl screams]
[man 5] Come on, give it to me!
I'll kill you, samurai!
-[breathing heavily]
-[screaming]
[tense music playing]
[gasping, panting]
[man 6 yelps]
Let's go.
[groans]
So you're not
who I'm after either, are you?
-[grunting]
-[screaming]
[laughs]
[girl groans]
[exhales]
[yelps, groans]
[laughing]
[man 7 screams]
[men laughing]
-Hmm.
-Oh.
-Ah.
-[chuckling]
[sinister music playing]
[man 1] Oh! [chuckles]
[man 2] If I may…
Our first participant has made it through.
Number 19, Kikuomi Ukyo.
Ah.
He's truly living up to the name,
"Guardian of the Nobility."
Former Guardian, right?
A lot has happened since.
Well, in any case,
he's clearly still skillful with a sword.
-Hm.
-He's putting on quite the show for us.
-[laughs]
-Well, this is only the beginning.
The real fun is yet to come.
[laughing]
-[panting]
-[woman screaming]
-[grunting]
-[shrieking]
This way!
[distant clamoring]
What's your name?
Katsuki Futaba.
And you, sir?
Saga Shujiro.
Huh?
We just need to make it to the gate now.
-Wait, but your tag--
-[footsteps approaching]
[ominous music playing]
[breath trembling]
[ominous music intensifies]
[man gurgles]
[chuckles softly]
Hey, calm down. You can relax, okay?
I've got no intention of fighting you.
I'll get his tag.
Just don't go slashing
at me all of a sudden.
Here you go. You take it.
What're you trying to pull here?
Listen, why aren't you going all out,
"Kokushu the Manslayer?"
[unsettling music playing]
Losing grip on your mind, are ya?
Insomnia. Hands shake, heart races…
The Boshin War sure got a lot
of people outright losing their minds.
But
if you
and that little miss intend to survive,
then you gotta start killing.
Well, it's your call, though.
Hold on!
Thank you so much.
[exhales]
I'm rooting for ya.
So hang in there, all right?
[footsteps receding]
We better get out of here now.
All right.
-[panting]
-[men groaning]
[dramatic music playing]
-[man 1 shrieks]
-[grunting]
Here we go!
You go ahead. Hurry!
Go!
-[breathing heavily]
-[roars]
[both grunting]
[laughing]
[screams]
[panting]
[groans]
-[shrieks]
-[yelps]
[clamoring]
[dramatic music intensifies]
[groaning]
[panting]
Congratulations on making it through.
Your wooden tags, please.
[Saga breathing heavily]
Uh, thank you so much, sir.
We're going to a friend's inn.
Stay alert.
Confirmation complete.
Safe travels.
[doors opening]
[ominous music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
[rain falling]
-[man 1] Ah, it's started to rain.
-[man 2] Oh! [chuckles]
[man 1] Quite the downfall we're getting.
Number 108, Saga Shujiro,
and number 120,
Katsuki Futaba, just made it through.
-Oh.
-Saga Shujiro.
Kokushu the Manslayer, right?
With a child in tow, huh? [chuckles]
-Wow. It's getting interesting!
-[men laugh]
Gentlemen. One more moment of your time.
-What is it? It was just getting good.
-[man 2] Mm.
I have just received a letter
from the mastermind.
Allow me to read it for you.
[dramatic music playing]
"To all who have agreed to this game,
this Kodoku,
I extend my deepest gratitude."
"The samurai,
they are capable
of nothing more than swinging swords."
"They boast their authority,
and they mistake it for true power."
"They haven't even noticed
how the world has left them behind."
"They drag out their days,
blind to their own pointlessness."
"So take pleasure."
"Indulge in this cruel dance
that will finally lay them to rest,
these ghosts who call themselves samurai."
[man 1 laughs]
[yelling, grunting]
-[riveting drums playing]
-[panting]
[dramatic music playing]
[man] It's been a while, hasn't it?
Kokushu.
Kanjiya Bukotsu…
What's it been, ten years?
I've been waiting for this moment.
I figured I'd find you here.
Let's do this…
Kokushu the Manslayer!
[grunting]
[laughs]
[breathing shakily]
-[laughs]
-[groans]
128 REMAINING
[dramatic music fades]
[ambient music playing]
[music fades]